<ArrayOfModuleData>

  <!-- 5. Safety Concerns -->
  <ModuleData>
    <Id>Safety Concerns</Id>
    <CourseId>HV Battery DISABLED</CourseId>
    <Anchor>
      <Type>Locator</Type>
      <LocatorId>Section 5</LocatorId>
    </Anchor>
    <LinkRootLocatorId>Section 5 Root</LinkRootLocatorId>
    <Requirements>
      <Modules>
        <string>Architecture</string>
      </Modules>
    </Requirements>

    <Instructions>

      <!-- Step 1 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The main purpose for you to know how the high voltage battery is built is to help keep you safe. There are also quite a few safety mechanisms built into the battery. Let’s look at those now.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 2 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>In the previous section, we saw how voltage builds. With all of that energy moving around inside, the high voltage battery can experience some considerable fluctuations in temperature and pressure. Good thing it has not one, but two vents on the rear of the battery! The vents are composed of a plastic plate, an umbrella valve, a breather valve, a vent patch and an exhaust deflector.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 3 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The plastic plate is like the chassis of the vent; it holds everything in place.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 4 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The umbrella valve opens outward to release pressure that has built up in the battery. Note, this valve opens one way only by design, which prevents outside dirt and debris from getting into the battery.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 5 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The breather valve allows for pressure equalization between the battery and the outside environment. Here’s an interesting fact for you: When our batteries travel by plane, the breather valve handles pressure changes in the battery during takeoff and landing. How practical!</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 6 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The vent patch is a super cool safety measure built into the vent. The patch disintegrates under high heat revealing 4 large openings. In the case of a thermal event, exposing the openings allows high pressure gases to exit the battery more quickly.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 7 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The exhaust deflector has two jobs. On a daily basis, it protects the umbrella valve and vent patch from damage. But, if there’s a thermal event, its job is to direct the hot air exiting the battery toward the side of the vehicle instead of up onto your feet.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 8 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>These changes in battery venting also impact some service tasks. Since the umbrella valve is now on the side instead of the bottom, you can no longer pull the umbrella valve to drain liquid inside of the battery. The good news is that the modules in Model 3 are raised up from the enclosure floor. This means that when the vehicle is sitting flat, it takes about 40 liters of liquid before it reaches the bottom of the module tub. That’s more than all of the coolant in Model 3!</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 9 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>Of course, the vehicle won’t always be flat. If the vehicle is tilted, coolant could leak into the module tub and cells, and nobody wants that! So, if you suspect liquid is in the battery, see service documentation for the proper procedure.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 10 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>In addition to battery venting, the battery for Model 3 has some other pretty cool new safety features.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 11 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The pyro disconnect is different from the pyro fuse found in Model S and X. It is not a standalone component like the fuse is. Instead, it works in conjunction with the high voltage shunt, and is externally triggered by the high voltage controller.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 12 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>There are several faults that trigger the pyro disconnect. The first is when there is a fault in the 12-volt power supply. There is an over-current fault, meaning the current in the high voltage battery is over the limit. Then there is an over-voltage fault, which triggers when voltage in one or more cells in the battery exceeds the limit, as well as an under-voltage fault, when the voltage of one or more cells drops below the limit. And last but not least, there is an over-temperature fault, which triggers if the temperature of one or more modules exceed its thermal threshold.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 13 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The pyro disconnect disconnects itself if it loses communication from the high voltage controller. Also, if the airbag has been deployed for any reason, the pyro disconnect opens, and therefore must be replaced.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 14 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>When removing and replacing the pyro disconnect, it is important to not damage the shunt or shunt connector.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 15 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The pre-charge mechanism is fundamentally different in Model 3 compared to S and X. In Model S and X, high voltage is used to precharge the high voltage battery. Model 3, however, uses the 12-volt battery and there is no precharge relay or resistor. Instead, Model 3 uses the DCDC converter in the power conversion system to step-up voltage from the 12-volt battery to match battery voltage.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 16 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The high voltage interlock loop (HVIL) of Model 3 is a bit more complex than S and X, but gets better diagnostic data. The new design of the loop also allows Model 3 to continue driving if the loop is faulted at the charge port. Although the HVIL loop is different, the fault detection algorithm is similar to what is used in S and X.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 17 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>There are three HVIL sub-loops, all powered by the high voltage controller. Each sub-loops starts at a HVC low voltage connector.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 18 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>Inside of the penthouse, the first interlock loop travels to the connectors for front drive unit if equipped, the rear drive unit,  the PTC heater and finally the compressor, then circles back to the HVC low voltage connector.</Text>
        <Highlights>
          <HighlightData>
            <DisplayName>Low voltage connector to HVC from vehicle</DisplayName>
            <ContentId>Model3</ContentId>
            <LocatorId>LV_Connector_To_HVC</LocatorId>
            <AssetId>PartPlaceholder</AssetId>
            <Delay>2</Delay>
          </HighlightData>
        </Highlights>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 19 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The second interlock loop goes to the charge port connector in the penthouse and back to the HVC low voltage connector. Short and sweet!</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 20 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>The final interlock loop is for the powertrain. It goes to the HVC vehicle interface connector, then to the rear drive unit, the compressor, the front drive unit (if equipped), and the PTC heater. It then makes its way back to HVC through the vehicle interface connector and onto the HVC Printed Circuit Board Assembly. There, it finds a 60 ohms resistor before closing the loop to chassis ground via a fastener in the enclosure.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 21 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>One last service note before I let you go; If you’re removing the penthouse cover, it means you’re also removing the fastener, opening up the HVIL loop.</Text>
      </InstructionData>

      <!-- Step 22 -->
      <InstructionData>
        <Text>That’s all you need to know about the high voltage battery in Model 3 for now. Thanks for joining!</Text>
      </InstructionData>
    
    </Instructions>
  </ModuleData>

</ArrayOfModuleData>